theadex.com 2017-12-27

# The ADEX GmbH - Leading DMP

We are very serious about data protection and are deeply committed to shielding Internet users’ privacy, to promoting their trust in Internet and Internet advertising. Data protection is an elemental component of professional data management and is systematically anchored in our technology. It goes without saying that our technology fully complies with data protection regulations in Germany and throughout Europe. In addition, we have pledged to adhere to applicable industry guidelines, including those, for example, collected by the Interactive Advertising Bureau.

**The ADEX adheres to the Principles of the iab Europe/ EDAA OBA Framework.**

We continuously examine possibilities to protect online users’ privacy while, at the same time, striving to provide appropriate advertising and customized online experiences as contracted by our clients.

The aim of this data privacy statement is to offer clearly understandable information on user data, which may have been collected either by us or by our partner businesses, and its relationship to our services and our partners’ Websites.

Below, we will describe how we collect and process user data in direct relationship to our services for our customers and partner businesses, such as advertising, which can be displayed on various Websites on the Internet. The implementation of cookies on numerous Websites, used to fulfill the services listed below, may lead to a collection of certain data. A cookie is a small text file that retains information for a limited period. Cookies can be used, for example, to recognize a user after their first visit, to provide him or her with dynamically customized content or to target him or her with specific, personally relevant advertising.

### Data collected via services and technology

The advertising that we administrate for our clients and partner businesses does not collect personal data from online users. Personal data is directly identifying information such as one’s name, address, telephone number and/or email address.

### Non-personal data collected via our technology

Non-personal data is collected to identify digital terminals that were previously used to interact online (computers, laptops, smartphones, tablets, PCs). By implementing non-personal data, terminals upon which advertising had been placed on behalf of one of our clients or partner businesses, can be identified. When non-personal data establishes a reference, this reference is to the digital terminal, not to a specific person. It is usually unknown who uses a terminal at any given time. By collecting, processing and using non-personal data we provide technology supported services, allowing the advertiser to present users with useful, customized and most important online announcements on numerous Websites, while at the same time inhibiting frequent and repetitive, and above all irrelevant advertising. For example, should we be convinced that a user is interested in Lifestyle & Clothing products or services; our technology then aids our clients in providing this user with online advertising targeting precisely the type of Lifestyle & Clothing products specific to this user. We collect non-personal data based on a user’s Web activities and his/her interaction with advertising that we administrate on behalf of our clients and partner businesses. Thereby, we both meet our goal to adapt and dynamically customize advertisements for users, as well as to contribute to analysis and research in general.

Non-personal data includes, among others, the Internet browser used, the operating system installed, the domain name, Websites visited or Website information that a user has viewed.

Non-personal data is collected by implementing cookies, pixels and the relevant technology administrated by our partner businesses. A cookie is a file on your browser that clearly identifies the browser you are using. As it is impossible to pinpoint a single user on a browser, we are speaking of browsers here, not users. A pixel represents a code used by a Website or third party to indicate a browser’s online activities. A pixel can document, for example, which particular Internet site a browser has visited. A pixel can also encompass additional non-personal data from an earlier period or a previous interaction. Although non-personal data cannot directly identify a user, we are nonetheless obligated to give users the opportunity to decide on the non-personal data we collect.

### Data protection in Europe and EU member countries

Among European Union member countries, there are varying views and assessments as to what is considered personal data. According to country-specific federal law in some countries, an IP (Internet protocol) address constitutes a personal data component. In these countries, we treat the IP address as personal data, provided we can determine that the user is a resident of this country.

In such countries, we insert a kind of switch which separates the user’s IP address from other data we have collected, and which is carried out by an independent third party. We will not track or retain any data when the Internet browser rejects cookies or the opt-out option is activated.

### Data transfer & disclosure

Personal data will not be sold, marketed or leased to third parties without the user’s consent. We transfer personal data to trustworthy externally contracted businesses that provide services for us. These businesses may only use this data and information to fulfill their contractual services.

We are permitted to transfer non-personal data and its related information collected by our services and technology to our clients, service providers and partner businesses. Furthermore, non-personal data from our clients can be used to provide individual advertising on participating Websites. As this data contains no personal identification, it cannot be used to establish personal contact or to identify a particular person.

As far as it is relevant, we recommend our clients and partner businesses to use compiled non-personal data in compliance with prevailing laws and regulations, and to publish data protection statements to inform users on the use of said collected data.

In singular cases, we can transfer user data to third parties when we have due reason to believe we are legally bound to do so in order to examine, deter or counteract assumed or actual prohibited activities. This includes, but is not limited to, instances of fraud and potential physical threats to the safety of other persons.

### The user can choose

We use administrated technology to perform our services via our clients, service providers and partner businesses. This technology may contain cookies. We believe that these tools lend our advertisers and us the opportunity to provide Internet users with a more pertinent and personally relevant online experience. Users can change their browser settings on their computers or other digital devices at any time to reject cookies. Under certain circumstances, this may infringe on other functions on the currently visited Website, limiting the optimal modulation of all offers and customized advertising on this particular Website.

### Data integrity and information security

To protect the retention and transferal of information from unauthorized access, we comply with generally recognized industry standards. This encompasses necessary physical, electronic and administrative measures which are required to protect data integrity, data access and data use. Each and every data saved on our server is treated as confidential. One must, however, take into account that our protective measures notwithstanding, a secure data transfer over the Internet cannot be guaranteed. Although we always strive to protect your data, we cannot promise absolute security.

Should you have any questions regarding this statement, please feel free to contact us via mail or email:

Mail@TheADEX.com
